Guide to the North Carolina Student Legislature, Duke University chapter records, 1965-1982 (bulk 1975-1979)
Duke University. University Archives
North Carolina Student Legislature, Duke University chapter records 1965-1982 (bulk 1975-1979)
Duke University. University Archives
North Carolina Student Legislature. Duke University chapter.
0.6 linear feet Extent: 600 Items
The North Carolina Student Legislature, the oldest active student legislature in the United States, was established in 1937. Contains the records of the Duke University chapter of the North Carolina Student Legislature, a student organization that presented legislation for possible enactment by the North Carolina General Assembly.
RL.01725
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The North Carolina Student Legislature, Duke University chapter records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977, 1989.
Historical Note
The North Carolina Student Legislature, the oldest active student legislature in the United States, was established in 1937. The organization represents North Carolina universities, colleges, and community colleges and offers students practical experience in politics and the legislative process. Under the leadership of a central government, member school delegations study current issues, write bills, and present resolutions for presentations at statewide meetings. The Student Governor and staff carry out all procedures at statewide meetings, which include delegates from all institutions with North Carolina Student Legislature chapters. Bills passed at annual statewide meetings are made available to the members of the North Carolina General Assembly.
The Duke University chapter has won several awards for best legislation, best bill, and best delegation. The 1979 Annual Session was hosted at Duke University. As of 2003, the Duke University chapter of the North Carolina Student Legislature is not active.
Collection Overview
Contains the records of the Duke University chapter of the North Carolina Student Legislature, a student organization that presented legislation for possible enactment by the North Carolina General Assembly. Types of materials include correspondence, legislative bills, conference proceedings, clippings, pamphlets, printed materials, a photograph, and award plaques. Major subjects include Duke University students, the North Carolina Student Legislature, student political activity, North Carolina General Assembly, resolutions, study and teaching of politics, parliamentary practice, and student groups.. Materials range in date from 1965 to 1982 (bulk 1975-1979).
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- Students -- Political activity; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc; Law -- North Carolina; Legislation -- North Carolina; North Carolina. General Assembly; North Carolina -- Politics and government -- Study and teaching (Higher).; North Carolina Student Legislature; North Carolina Student Legislature. Duke University chapter; Parliamentary practice -- Study and teaching -- North Carolina; Resolutions, Legislative
Related Material
Duke University College Republicans records
University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Session proceedings, 1965
  - Session proceedings, 1976-1977
  - Session proceedings, 1978-1979
  - Compendium, 40th Annual Session, 1977
  - Clippings, 1973, 1979
  - Pamphlets, 1978, 1982-1983, undated
  - Award plaques (Box 2)
    - Best Legislation, 1965
    - Best Delegation -- Large College, 1968
    - Best Delegation -- Large School, 1971
    - Best Bill -- Large School, 1972
    - Best Delegation, 1973